Fushi leads a life of peace,
living together with Gugu and the others.
Little by little, the stimulants built up.
The accumulated stimuli and a fight with Gugu
lead Fushi to take Pioran's advice
to look for Gugu, who had run away.
The two of them are reunited once again.
TO YOUR ETERNITY
I heard it's over here.
So this is where the monster lives?
But nobody's here.
Scary...
-It appeared!
-Monster!
We did it, Fushi!
The greater the stimulus,
the deeper it is imprinted in one's memory.
For example, encountering a monster...
One boy became friends with a monster.
Did you see them?
Their faces were hilarious!
Gugu.
Not going back? To Grandpa Beer's place.
No.
Didn't you hear?
Grandpa Beer stuffed alcohol inside of me.
Gugu!
What... I... can't... move...
EPISODE 9: DEEP MEMORY
I haven't eaten anything in so long...
Fushi, do you have anything?
No...
I see...
I made it!
Gugu, I made it!
Hold on. I'll make more!
Got it! Eat up!
This is great!
You can even make food now?
The greater the stimulus was,
the easier it was for Fushi to replicate it.
-The greater the stimulus,
the deeper it is imprinted in one's memory.
-Amazing. Anything else?
-That's all.
-Oh, I see.
Yet, depending on his future growth,
the day may come when Fushi is able
to replicate
-even the smallest of stimuli.
-Ah, I can't eat anymore...
Joan?
Myrr! Did you run away from home again?
Joan.
No, Fushi. This is Myrr.
This is Rynn's dog.
Who is Joan anyway?
Joan...
A person said that name when they saw my face.
Then Joan must have been your name.
Was it your parent who called you that?
I don't know.
But that person was my first person.
They became hollow, unable to move,
and I became them.
I see...
So your appearance
originally came from another person.
And that person died.
Died?
Yes. It means they passed away.
You can turn into a little girl, can't you?
Did she die too?
That huge bear and the wolf as well?
What is "death"?
It's the hollowness you spoke of.
But once it happens, you can never turn back.
That's death.
You were reacting to pain
when you created things, right?
Would you react to emotional pain as well?
For instance,
if I died and you were emotionally hurt,
you would be able to become me.
Something like that, right?
I think.
That's great, though. It's really great!
Why?
Even if I die,
at least you'll continue to think of me, right?
Yes.
You know, I'm all alone.
If I had grown up in a normal household...
There would be someone
who would prepare food for me every day.
I would have a bed to sleep in every night.
A mother to nurse me when I get sick.
A father asking me how I was doing every day.
Older twin sisters who would tease
but play with me.
A big brother who would teach me lots of things.
To live a life where people would remember me.
It'd be a matter of course.
But... But then...
One day, I would feel that discomfort.
Come, children!
We received some cake. Let's eat it together.
Yay! You didn't forget our promise!
Cherry cake, right? My favorite!
Wait, Gugu.
Wait.
Such are the rules.
Hm? Why are both of you waiting over there?
Come quickly and have some cake with us!
Yes. Thank you very much!
After a while, we had to move far away
due to my father's work.
But they didn't take us with them.
Well, I guess it's just the two of us now.
All right. Let's go find work elsewhere.
I thought they were my family,
but they were just my employers.
The only one who actually
thought of me was my brother.
Ever since we became alone,
he has always been kind to me.
But now, even that is in the past.
In the end, I'm alone.
But now you're here.
I'm sorry for what I did, Fushi...
I'm sorry for hurting you.
If I die, become me, Fushi.
I'm a bit sleepy now...
Did you eat too much?
Right now, I'm really happy.
After all, you're worrying about me.
You thought of me, and now you're here for me.
I feel like...
that's what family should be.
Gugu...
Found you! What are you doing here?
Rynn?
I spent so much time looking for you!
How did you find us?
I heard Myrr.
Myrr likes to run away too much.
Why won't you come back?
What are you saying, "why won't I come back"?
I am a victim here!
The old man said he repented.
And he'll take out the thing inside for free!
For free?
Obviously!
So we should go back.
Come on, let's go.
Wait!
Why does everyone want me back?
Why?
Because we all need you.
Because we love you!
Really?
Even you?
Yes.
Grandpa, Grandma, food is ready!
-Bleh!
-Yuck!
If you're going to complain, make it yourself!
Nah.
Too lazy.
I don't want to do this either!
But I won't go back.
I threw away the mask.
That means I threw away my humanity as well.
Wasn't that supposed
to be a gag for the customers?
Sorry, I lied.
It was to hide the scars on my face.
I'm so sorry... And you're still hiding it?
What are you doing?
Horrible! Pervert! Evil!
Why are you sticking to the tree
like some sort of bug?
Who cares about your face?
It matters to me!
I don't want it to be seen!
By you...
Even though you were showing it off before?
Fushi, please be quiet for a bit!
What? So you just won't show it to me?
Well, that's not really...
Then if you have a mask,
will you stop acting like a bug?
I'll go get it. So tell me where you left it.
Oh, where could I have left it...
Gugu.
What?
You always look like your heart hurts
when you talk to Rynn.
Will you feel better with the mask?
Wh... What...
What are you saying?
I'll go find it!
Don't leave me behind!
What a weird guy.
But he's so nice.
Hey, should I show you my wound?
My wound is pretty bad.
Maybe you'll realize your wound
isn't bad enough for you to hide it.
W... Wait!
See? Isn't it horrible?
Of course not!
Wha...
That's so mean! I was so worried about it!
Compared to my injury,
that looks like a scratch!
-Then show me your injury!
-No! No!
I can well affirm that your wound
is nearly completely healed.
So why are you worried about it? Stupid!
There's a limit to over-reacting!
What...
You say the same things my parents do...
Oh... I'm sorry...
Is it not going well with your parents?
It doesn't matter what my life is like.
Because I'd be over-reacting.
Well... That's... Don't cry...
Fushi, come back quick...
They treat me like some kind of pet.
They always want things to go their way.
It's so mean!
My favorite color is purple,
but they always buy me green stuff
because it's the family color!
Isn't green fine?
That's not all.
One time I painted a picture,
and my mother hired an art teacher.
I didn't like that, so I started sewing.
And she hired a sewing teacher.
I just want to do things freely...
There were always people surrounding me.
If I sneezed,
they would come to check my temperature.
They'd make me eat food every day
even when I didn't want to.
They'd comb my hair four times a day.
Whenever I went outside
to escape that stifling house,
an attendant would follow.
I've never had any time to be alone!
As if I haven't been recognized
as an individual at all in that house.
That's dumb.
You have some nice parents, don't you?
You're the one that's spoiled.
You must have it tough.
So tough that you need to chalk up
others' consideration for you as misfortune
so you can gloat about how unlucky you are.
Don't misunderstand!
I wouldn't expect you to understand my values!
Even this wound!
I only got it
because I was born into that house!
What?
Someone pushed me from behind.
They said it might have been someone
who has a grudge against my father.
And they wouldn't worry about me at all!
You're wrong.
What? Did you say I was wrong?
No. I said that you were stupid.
Hey! How many times
are you going to call me stupid in one day?
Hey, Myrr, did I say anything bad?
No, woof!
Hey, how did you get an injury on your face?
I won't tell you.
If I tell you, you'll hate me.
What do you mean?
Do you like me?
I won't tell you.
If I tell you, you'll hate me.
You won't tell me anything.
I'm a monster. That's all you need to know.
Um... Hey! I brought this mask
as a present for you!
Grandpa said
this was a legendary folk mask or something!
Sounds amazing, right?
Use it if you'd like.
I don't need something like this!
You're pretty stupid too.
I don't care whether
you're a human or a monster.
You know, either way, you're you, aren't you?
Whether you expose everything
or hide everything,
it's weird either way. But I like it.
That's you.
You're only you.
So come out.
Do you intend never to look me in the eyes?
I want to get to know you better.
Even if you need to wear a mask
all the way through.
You know... The wind is nice today.
Fushi's late, isn't he?
Should we wait? Should we find him?
Let's go.
Sorry for before. I said some mean things.
I don't recall.
Found it!
Is it fun pretending to be human?
Your enemies are always waiting for an opening.
Be careful.
I tossed away the mask just ahead,
so Fushi should be there.
Are you sure we won't miss each other?
Don't worry. He'll find us.
How do you know?
Well, because he's like that.
What? I don't get it.
Let's go back, Ms. Rynn.
No! Let go!
Who is that?
Some rascal being paid to abduct me!
How much did they offer for capturing me?
Oh, the Cropp girl.
-She ran away again?
-Let me go!
Let go of me!
No!
Run!
Did you run away from home?
Yes, that's right.
My father probably hired 20 or so guys
to run around the streets and find me.
Why did you run away?
Tell me the reason.
Hm? Haven't I already?
You mean what we spoke about earlier?
Yes. Something wrong with that?
No...
So was this mask
to prevent them from finding you?
Yes.
I didn't want to be dragged back
before finding you guys.
Sorry for making up the story
about it being a present.
Are you disappointed?
I'll return it.
Thanks for lending me the mask.
I think I understand you a bit more.
Don't worry. I won't look.
It doesn't really...
Thanks.
I found it!
Fushi!
All right.
Let's head back to Grandpa Beer's place.
Really? You just said you didn't want to.
Isn't that the best place for you to be?
Yes, but... Aren't you angry about what he did?
I don't really care anymore.
It's not like I've forgiven
what was done to me,
or that I don't think it was wrong.
I just no longer care about
my own circumstances.
That's all.
That's why I can go back.
Let's go.
My lady!
Where did you run off to?
Don't try to fool us with this mask!
Come, let's go back.
Your father is worried.
Might you have the wrong person?
I haven't heard of a "Rynn".
As cute as always.
But I never said anything about "Rynn".
Please stop this, my lady.
I don't want to... It's such a pain...
Just ignore them!
My lady! My lady!
She's coming!
It'll be troublesome if she chases us back.
Fushi! Please!
Wait!
My lady...
What? Who is this child?
Oh, no! What should I do?
Hurts...
-She's bleeding! This is bad!
-Hurts...
There! The house is right ahead!
Where's Fushi?
Don't worry. He'll come in a bit!
I wonder.
Will he really?
I doubt he will return.
For two reasons.
First,
he has acquired nothing useful
since his last battle.
Second,
the first to strike wins.
What was that cry?
Fushi is doing it flashily...
Someone help!
A monster!
-A monster?
-I'll go take a look!
-Go back to the house!
-Wait!
Don't leave me...
I said... I can go back alone.
All right. Be careful!
Okay... You too!
Fushi!
What? Blood?
Fushi! Fushi! Fushi!
What is this?
The unknown enemy
makes a reappearance.
Fushi was attacked in the forest.
Gugu rushes to save him.
A bond between brothers
was formed in the moment of resurrection.
EPISODE 10: NEW FAMILY